Theatre, Department of; Records ua609
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Department of Theatre Records1948-1984
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. Theatre Department.
ua609
7.167 cubic ft.
Originally the Department of Speech and Dramatic Art, it encompassed the disciplines of Dramatic Art; Rhetoric and Public Address; Radio, Television and Film; and Speech Pathology and Audiology. The Department is responsible for the operation of the State University Theatre, is closely affiliated with the Northeastern New York Speech Center, and is the sponsor of a number of course-related student organizations
Administrative History
The Department of Theatre at the State University of New York at Albany has its roots in a course entitled Dramatics, first offered by the English Department of the New York State Teachers College in 1915. This course emphasized theory and practice of amateur stage presentation with production of at least one standard play each half year [New York State College For Teachers, Annual Circular and Announcement, 1915-1916, p.60]. Courses in Drama and Theatre continued to be offered by the English Department until 1963 when the Department of Speech and Dramatic Art was established, chaired by Paul B. Pettit.
The Department of Speech and Dramatic Art encompassed the disciplines of Dramatic Art; Rhetoric and Public Address; Radio, Television and Film; and Speech Pathology and Audiology. In addition, it was responsible for the operation of the State University Theatre, was closely affiliated with the Northeastern New York Speech Center, and was the sponsor of a number of course-related student organizations [State University of New York at Albany, General Catalogue, 1963-1964, p.221].
In 1969, the Department of Speech and Dramatic Art was dissolved and the Department of Theatre was established. Recognizing that the "lively arts" drew strength from past endeavors and validity from the contemporary ethic, the department sought to inter-relate the literature, history and criticism of the theatre with an extensive program in production. The State University Theatre and the Center for Theatre Services, both located in the university's Performing Arts Center, are functions of the department [State University of New York at Albany, Undergraduate Bulletin, 1969-1970, p.124].
Department Chairs
Paul B. Pettit, 1963/64-1970/71
Jarka Burian, 1970/71-1973/74
James Symons, 1974/75-1976/77
Jarka Burian, 1977/78
Albert Asermely, 1978/79-1983/84
Jerome Hanley, 1984/85-1987/88
Langdon Brown, 1988/89-
J. Kevin Doolen, 2004/05
Scope and Contents
The records of the Department of Theatre consist of the general Subject Files and a separate series titled Productions. The general Subject Files of the Theatre Department contain correspondence of the Department Chair, memoranda, reports, committee minutes, photographs, publicity materials, as well as documents used in the planning and expansion of the department. Also contained in the files are student papers submitted to Professor Paul B. Pettit. The series entitled Productions consists of programs, scripts, and other production material from plays produced by the Theatre Department.
In addition to the routine administrative concerns of an academic department the files contain extensive documentation of the development of the department's summer theatre program, which was originally founded in 1952 as the Arena Summer Theatre. The program was suspended in 1968, and revived as the Summer Theatre, under which name it continues to this day. The collection also contains early correspondence files relating to the formation of the Children's Theatre founded at the University in 1965, subsequently the Empire State Youth Theatre Institute of SUNY, headquartered at the New York State Performing Arts Center. The Empire State Youth Theatre Institute was reaffiliated with the University in 1989, and changed it's name to the New York State Theatre Institute in 1990. The files also contain the correspondence relating to the New York State Community Theatre Association, 1953-1971.
Arrangement of the Collection
Divided into two topical file series
Acquisition Information
These records were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives by the Department of Theatre. Some playbills were acquired independently by the University Archives.
Related Materials
See also the University Archives Vertical File for the Dramatic Arts Association, 1919-1940 for early play programs. Related collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives include the papers of former Department of Theatre chairs Jarka Burian (UA-902.017) and Paul Pettit (UA -- 902.007). Pettit was the founder of the Arena Summer Theatre and the first chair of the Department of Theatre.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Theater -- Study and teaching -- New York (State) -- Albany.; Universities and colleges -- New York (State) -- Albany -- Departments.; Playbills.; Correspondence.; Memorandums.; Budgets.; Minutes.; Publications.; Clippings.; Bulletins.; Photographs.; Programs.; Account books.; Bylaws.; Press releases.; Art; Music; UAlbany Academic Departments; State University of New York at Albany.
- Subject Files, 1948-1978; 1984; 1; 6 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  The Subject Files of the Theatre Department contain correspondence of the Department Chair, various committee minutes, academic planning documents and general administrative documents collected and generated during the years 1948-1978, 1984. Major projects of the department for which documentation exists include clippings, correspondence, publicity, course material, account ledgers, and Annual Production Reports, 1958-1969 of the Arena Summer Theatre and the Summer Theatre, 1972-1977. Also contained are early records relating to the planning and development of the Children's Theatre; Paul B. Pettit's involvement in the New York State Community Theatre Association; and the development of an Experimental Theatre program, 1969-1977.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically and chronologically thereafter.
  - AD HOC Committee--Play Selections, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Administrative Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Affirmative Action, 1973 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - American Specialists Program, 1960 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Analysis, Script, Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1971-1975; 1977-1978 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Arena Summer Theatre, 1962 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Application Forms and Course, Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Announcements, 1961 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Business, 1966 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Business Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Clippings, Programs, 1952-1966 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Clippings, 1958-1963 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Clippings, 1960 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Correspondence, 1961; 2 folders (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16-17)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Course Materials, 1959 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Course Materials, 1960 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Course Outline, 1956 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Daily Account Sheets, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Ledger, 1954 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Ledger, 1955; 1956; 1957 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Memos, 1955 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Notes, 1967 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Press Book, 1958 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Press Book, 1959 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Press Book, 1960 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Press Book, 1961 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Press Book, 1963 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Press Book, 1967 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Annual Producers Report, 1958 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Annual Producers Report, 1959 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Arena Summer Theatre-Annual Producers Report, 1963 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Annual Producers Report, 1964 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Arena Summer Theatre Annual Producers Report, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Annual Producers Report, 1966 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Annual Producers Report, 1958; 1963-1964; 1969; 1972-1977 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Programs, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Publicity, 1952-1954 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Publicity, 1956 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Publicity Releases, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Publicity, 1955-1956 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Reviews, Photos, Correspondence, 1967 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Arena Summer Theatre--Security Regulations, 1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Association for Cultural Exchange (A.C.E.)--Junior Semester, 1970 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Bard College Evaluation, 1979 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Bard College--New York State Inspection Team Visit, 1979 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - British Theatre, 1972 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Budget Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Budget Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - By-Laws, 1974 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - By-Laws, 1975 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Calendar Information, 1966-1970 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Chamber Theatre, 1965 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Chancellor's Inauguration, 1971 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Children's Theatre, 1965-1974 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Children's Theatre, 1968-1969 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Children's Theatre, 1972 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Children's Theatre, 1974 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Children's Theatre--ASSITEJ, 1970-1972 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Children's Theatre--ASSITEJ, 1971-1972 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Children's Theatre--ASSITEJ, 1972 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Children's Theatre -- Budget, 1972-1974 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Children's Theatre--Trip to Russia, 1972-1975 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - City Center, 1973 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Communications, School of--Proposed, 1965-1968 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Convocation of the Arts, 1967-1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Cooperstown Project, 1963 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1967 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence--M. McCandless, 1970 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Correspondence--M. McCandless, 1971-1972 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Courses Submitted and Approved, 1969-1973 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - DADA--by Veronica Price, 1952 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Departmental Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, 1966-1971 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Departmental Meetings--Agenda, Minutes, 1972-1974 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Departmental Meetings, 1974 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Departmental Meetings, 1975 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Departmental Meetings, 1976 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Departmental Meetings, 1977 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Departmental Memos, 1970-1975 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Departmental Agendas, Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Departmental Minutes, Memos, Committees, 1971-1972 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Departmental Photographs, undated Departmental Workload Analysis, 1972 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Directory of Offerings, Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
    Directory of Offerings in Speech, Theatre..., 1967 Dramatics and Arts Council, 1955-1957 Dramatics and Arts Council, 1956-1957 Dramatics and Arts Council, 1960-1966.
  - Drummond, A.D.-"Practical Suggestions for the Actor", Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - East End Podium Extension, 1969-1971 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - English Department--Proposed Courses, 1958 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - English Department--Official Communications, 1958 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Experimental Theatre, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Experimental Theatre, 1969-1975 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Experimental Theatre, 1970-1977 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Faculty, Atkinson, Clinton, 1972 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Faculty, Drummond, A. M., 1948-1952 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Faculty, Golden, Edward, 1977 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Faculty, Krivitski, Antony, 1975-1977 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Faculty, McMorris, Barbara, 1978 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Faculty, Muir, Jean, 1978 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Faculty, Oliver, Josephine, 1976 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Faculty, Pulawski, Marilyn, 1978 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Faculty, Roach, Joseph, 1973 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Faculty, Sheehan, Michael, 1976 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Faculty, Sugarman, Robert, 1971-1972 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Faculty, Symons, James, 1977 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Faculty, 1972-1973 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Faculty-Student Liason Committee, 1978 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Faculty-Student Survey, 1970 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Fulbright Grant, 1959-1961 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Futterer, Agnes E. Lecturer, 1968-1969 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Futterer-Kirkland Historical Notes, Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Graduate Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Graduate Committee, 1973 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Graduate Committee, 1974 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Graduate Committee, 1975 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Graduate Evaluation, 1973 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Graduate Evaluation, 1974 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Guest Artists, 1974-1975 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Guest Speakers, 1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - In Search of Thespis -- Symposium, 1970 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Laboratory Theatre, 1955 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Library Committee, 1972 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Mask, The--Data on issues, 1918-1923 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Masters Program--Review Materials, 1975-1976 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Memos to Staff, 1974-1977 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Microfilm Project, 1959 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Middle States Preparatory, 1970-1971 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous, 1967-1968 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Misericords, 1971 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Nellhaus, Gerhard, 1961-1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - New Curricula -- Dramatic Art, 1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - New Curricula -- Public Address, 1964-1965 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - New Curricula -- Speech Correction, 1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - News Releases-Sources, 1964-1965 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - News Releases, 1970 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - New York State Council on the Arts -- Theatre Meeting, 1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - New York State Teachers Association--Eastern Zone, Speech Section, 1958 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Nominating Committee, 1973-1976 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - New York State English Council Annual Meeting-Rochester, 1959 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - New Yrk State Speech Association, 1957 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - New York State Community Theatre Association, 1953-1959 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - New York State Community Theatre Association, 1960; 3 folders (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 42-44)
  - New York State Community Theatre Association, 1961 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - New York State Community Theatre Association, 1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - New York State Community Theatre Association, 1963 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - New York State Community Theatre Association, 1953-1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - New York State Community Theatre Association, 1969-1970 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - New York State Community Theatre Association -- Journal Material, 1960 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - New York State Community Theatre Association--Meeting, 1957 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - New York State Community Theatre Association--Press Releases, 1964-1971 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - New York State Community Theatre Association--Regional Meeting, 1958 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - New York State Community Theatre Association--Zone Meeting, 1958 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - New York State Teachers College Faculties Association -- Speech Areas, 1959 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Office of the President, 1968-1971 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Open Theatre, 1970 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Opera Workshop, 1975 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - P.A.C. Committee, 1970-1973 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - P.A.C. Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - P.A.C. Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - P.A.C. Committee, 1975 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - P.A.C. Dedication, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - P.A.C. Scheduling, 1969-1971 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Page Hall -- Dimmer Panel, 1961 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Photographs--Assorted, Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Play Analysis, Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Play Production Possibilities, 1956-1962 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Production Budgets, 1970-1971 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Production Committee, 1969-1972 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Production Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Production Committee Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Productions, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Programs, 1952-1955 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Proposals--Poetry, Programs, etc, 1968 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Publicity Clippings, 1972 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Publicity Clippings File, 1973 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Publicity Clippings, 1974 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Religious Drama, 1959 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Reports, Correspondence, 1952 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Research Foundation, 1959 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Research Foundation, 1960 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Research Foundation, 1961 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Royalties/Contract Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Sound--In the Theatre, 1961 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Sound System -- Page Hall, 1957 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Smithsonian Puppet Theatre, 1969 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - State College Theatre--Clippings, 1960 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - State College Theatre Account, 1960 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - State College Theatre Alumni Association, 1961 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - State University Albany Theatre--Press Releases, 1967-1972 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - State University Theatre--Publicity, 1969-1970 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - State University Theatre--Publicity, 1973-1975 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - State University Theatre--Publicity, 1975-1977 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Student Enrollment Survey, 1970 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Summer Orientation, 1974 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Summer Theatre, 1972 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Summer Theatre, 1973 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Summer Theatre, 1974 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Summer Theatre, 1975; 2 folders (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13-14)
  - Summer Theatre, 1976 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Summer Theatre Productions, 1953-1984 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - S.U.N.Y. Theatre Association, 1968-1971 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - S.U.N.Y. Theatre Association, 1973-1975 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - S.U.N.Y. Theatre History, Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - S.U.N.Y. Theatres-Saratoga Practicum, 1970 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - S.U.N.Y.A. University Theatre, 1975-1978 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Temporary State Commission on the Capital City, 1962 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Theatre Alumni Association, 1963-1973 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Theatre [Dramatics] Council Budget, 1962-1968 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Theatre [Dramatics] Council Budget, 1969 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Theatre [Dramatics] Council Budget, 1970-1972 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Theatre du Josefstadt--Austrian Company, 1975 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Theatre Papers-Students, 1942; 1948; 1959; 1961 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Theatre Questionnaire -- Alumni Results, 1977 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Theatre Questionnaire--Results, 1977 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Undergraduate Bulletins, 1971-1977 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Undergraduate Committee, 1972 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Undergraduate Committee, 1973 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - University Theatre--Community Relations and Releases, 1964-1967 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - The Wig--Dramatics and Arts Newsletter, 1955-1956 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 35)
- Production Files, 1953-1985; 2; 1 cubic foot
  The Production Files of the Theatre Department contain scattered scripts, play programs, press releases, photographs, cast lists, and production material.
  - Ala-Ed-Din, 1970 (Box 1 (2-Production Files), Folder 1)
  - Alchemist, 1965 (Box 1 (2-Production Files), Folder 2)